<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>CAST</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Syntax: cast '&lt;spell&gt;' [&lt;object&gt; | &lt;victim&gt; ]

&quot;Cast&quot; is a command used to indicate that a spell is being created. It is
the act of invoking the gods or calling upon magical powers inside the
individual. Some spells may only be cast on the caster, and therefore you
do not need to indicate a target for the spell. If you are casting a spell
upon yourself, you may substitute for your name &quot;me&quot; or &quot;self.&quot; All spell
names must be enclosed by ' '. For Magic-User subclasses, you must have a
spellbook containing the spell you want to cast in order to memorize it.
For Priest sub-classes, you may simply pray for your spells. Undeads, 
except for Gargoyles, must assimilate spells. Finally, Druids regain their
spells by communing them.

Examples:       cast 'burning hands' &lt;victim&gt;
                cast 'teleport'
                cast 'strength' me

If you are casting an offensive spell while in combat, and the target is
the enemy you are fighting, the spell will automatically be directed at the
enemy without having to define a target.

There is help available for each individual spell (see examples below).

Examples:      	help &quot;cure light&quot;
                help &quot;minor creation&quot;
                help &quot;energy drain&quot;

NOTE:  You can abbreviate the spell name when casting it.  For example,

                &gt; cast 'lightning bolt' &lt;monster&gt;

                could be abbreviated as:

                &gt; cast 'ligh' &lt;monster&gt;

You must be careful however when abbreviating to insure that the correct
spell is cast because many spells have similar names and the abbreviations
may not be obvious at once. Experimentation in a safe forum is the best
idea to insure that no disasters occur.
</content>
	<see-also file="spellsystem"/>
	<see-also file="spellslot"/>
	<see-also file="spellcircle"/>
	<see-also file="spellfailure"/>
	<see-also file="magic"/>
	<see-also file="memorize"/>
	<see-also file="pray"/>
	<see-also file="assimilate"/>
	<see-also file="tupor"/>
	<see-also file="commune"/>
	<see-also file="caster"/>
</help-file>
