<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>CENTAUR</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Centaurs are a half horse, half human race, with the upper half looking
like a human, and the lower half looking like a large draft horse. Centaurs
are quiet, forest dwelling creatures from a far off forest covered land.
Centaurs are a good race, and thus will be on the good side of the race
wars on Duris. Being a seclusive race, centaurs are shy and slow to trust.
Because of this, only their own race and those of the elven and half-elven
race may enter their hometown. All other races are considered invaders,
and will be attacked on sight!

Centaur class list: Warrior, Ranger, Druid, Shaman.

Stats: Centaur are a very powerful race and have both great strength and
       hearty constitution. Being 1/2 horse, they can out-distance any
       other race in the world, being able to travel miles a day without
       growing tired. They are not known for their wit or wisdom however
       and thus seldom dabble in the mystic arts. They do however make
       decent Druids and Shamans, due to their high constitution. Centaur
       are so good with the bow that they gain a +2 to hit and a +1 on
       damage, due to their great strength. Their flighty nature and
       attunement with their environment allows them to be always AWARE and
       thus it is difficult to backstab them.

Centaur innate abilities: infravision, doorkick, stampede

Weakness: Centaurs are a flighty race by nature, and thus ALWAYS flee when
          they hear the roar of a dragon, and in fact, flee quite a lot.
          Also, given their odd body shape, Centaur cannot bash nor can
          they BE based by any race, save the Ogre, due to his great size
          and strength. Centaur can't wear anything on their legs, and can
          only wear horseshoes on their feet. They can however wear a ring
          on their tail.

Centaur have been known to sometimes allow their close friends to ride on 
their backs, but they must be wearing a saddle, and give consent.
</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="infravision"/>
	<see-also file="innate"/>
	<see-also file="rearkick"/>
	<see-also file="stampede"/>
	<see-also file="archery"/>
</help-file>
