<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>CHARING "CITY OF ELVES"</title>
<content>
Charing is a small quiet forest community set in the northeastern corner of
Evermeet Continent that welcomes Elf, Centaur and Half-elf visitors. What
it lacks in size it makes up in beauty. Massive oak tress filled with
birds, small creatures and sparkling rivers make for the most serene 
setting. In the southeast section of the forest stands the Great Tree of 
Charing. Here is your gateway to the city above.

The Palace of the City of Charing is the host for many of the Elven 
dignitaries. Towering behind a pair of impressive gates, the spires are 
truly one to be seen. Just south of the Palace on the &quot;Way of the Royals&quot;
is the Warriors guild, where the impressive guardians of Charing train.
Continuing south is a beautiful fountain in the shape of a mermaid, this is
also the center of town. Heading down the east trail takes you past several
entertainment areas. You have the Grovetree Theatre, the home of the
renowned Grovesinger's Troupe, who are said to give the highest quality of
performance almost anywhere. After the performance shop by and let Nelanna
serve up some of the local brew.

Continuing down the trail is the Tower of High Magic. Hundreds of students 
a year stop here hoping to study with the most respected sorceress 
Morlyntra and her brother conjurer Morlander. When the hunger strikes you, 
head back to the west of the trail and stop by The Blue Dragon Restaurant.
Gaston Reglia the master chef is noted for his elegant meals and the 
seating is limited! West of the restaurant is the Rangers guild. A small 
wooden structure that offers Rangers from all around a safe place to train 
and hold council. If you would like to join them in their daily hunts, 
Alkatia's Fletcher shop just south of the fountain offers a fine selection
of longbows, arrows and quivers. Keep going south of Alkatia's and you'll
find the Bank of Charing and finally you can settle the end of the day at
the Olde Inn of Charing across the street.

Amenities:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Inn, Bank, Equipment Lockers, Armor Shop, Weapon Shop, Supply Store, Pet
Store, Magic Shop, Restaurant.

Teachers:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Warrior, Ranger, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Conjurer, Bard, Thief.

Statistics:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Written by Melkivar, Evermeet Continent, 1-20 suggested levels (garden and
forest animals), Warning: only Elf, Centaur and Half-Elves may enter.

</content>
	<see-also file="hometowns"/>
</help-file>
