<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>CONSTRUCT</title>
	<category type="Command"/>
<content>
Construct is the basis for building both houses and guildhalls. Funds must
be kept on hand while using this command. It takes a varying amount of
money and time to construct something, dependent on where you would like to
build it. Everything is saved through a crash, though, so fear not.

<Y>construct guildhall</Y>
  Cost: varies on terrain
  This will construct your guildhall on the current worldmap location you
  are standing on.  Only Leaders have this ability.  The guildhall will
  be a down exit from your current location and will consist of two rooms.

<Y>construct room &lt;exit dir&gt; &lt;door|nodoor&gt; [door keyword]</Y>
  Cost: 1k
  This option will build a room with an exit from the room you are standing
  in into the new room. You must use a valid exit direction &lt;n s e w&gt; and
  tell it if you want a door or nodoor. If you want a door, you should
  specify the keyword. e.g.: construct n door curtain
  <R>Note: The doors are bugged, do not use them</R>

Once you have the initial building in place, there are various addictions
available for you.

<Y>construct name &lt;</Y><W>A</W><B>n</B><M>s</M><G>i</G><Y> room name&gt;</Y>
  Cost: 50     
  Names the current room. You are able to use ANSI color in this.

<Y>construct describe</Y>
  Cost: 10
  This option will put you into the edit system similar to bulletin
  boards, and when you are done will set the description of the room
  appropriately.

<Y>construct inn</Y>
  Cost: 5k
  Builds an inn in the current room. Only one inn is allowed per guildhall.

<Y>construct heal</Y>
  Cost: 3k
  Builds a accelerated healing room in the current room.

<Y>construct teleporter &lt;target&gt;</Y>
  Cost: 20k
  Builds a teleporter between two halls. You must have a target standing 
  in the room of the other hall, and this command will build the teleporter
  from your room to his room and back. A guild may have up to 2 teleporters
  per hall, but the guildhall must contain 10 rooms before a teleporter
  can be placed within it.

<Y>construct mouth </Y><R>DISABLED</R>
  Cost: 500
  Builds a magic mouth in current room. This acts as an alarm and will
  broadcast when someone not in your guild is in that room. Only one
  magic mouth can be built per guildhall.

<Y>construct fountain</Y>
  Cost: 500
  Builds a fountain in current room. Only one fountain of any type may be
  built per guildhall.

<Y>construct holy|unholy</Y>
  Cost: 3k
  Builds a holy/unholy fountain in the current room. Only one fountain of 
  any type may be built per guildhall.

<Y>construct cabinet </Y><R>DISABLED</R>
  Cost: 2,500  
  This option will create a cabinet in the house (not available for use in
  guildhalls, please use construct chest), allowing you to store things in
  it. Any number of cabinets can be built.

<Y>construct chest</Y>
  Cost: 5k
  Builds a chest in the current room. Any number of chests may be in each 
  room and guildhall.
  <R>Note: Most chest functions are better served with lockers in hometowns.</R>

<Y>construct shop</Y>
  Cost: 10k
  Builds a shop in the current room.

<Y>construct secret entrance </Y><R>DISABLED</R>
  Cost: 10,000 
  This option will hide the entrance to your house (not available for
  guildhalls).

<Y>construct cleric | mage | warrior</Y>
  Cost: 10k
  Used to construct mage, cleric, or warrior golems. Golems will be placed
  in the entryway of your guild, no matter where you execute this command.
  Only 4 golems can be built per guildhall.

Note: Many commands may now be used to move options from one room to
another. Doing a new &quot;construct fountain&quot; for example will cost 0, and will
move the fountain spot to your current room. All moves of this sort will
take place the next time the game reboots.

</content>
	<see-also file="guild"/>
	<see-also file="guildhall"/>
	<see-also file="society"/>
</help-file>
