<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>"DROW ELF"</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Living far beneath the surface, deep within the bowels of the Underdark,
drow elves are a swift-moving, crafty, remorselessly wicked people ruled by
a society of priestesses who serve the demonic Spider Queen, Lloth. The
drow are an extremely intelligent race, and their abilities and ambition
are feared and loathed by races throughout the Realms, particularly grey
elves, their distant cousins and blood enemies.

Because of the length of time they spend below the surface, drow are hurt
by the natural light of the sun and the light of fire. To compensate, they
have permanent ultravision, allowing them to see in total darkness.
However, they seldom travel to the surface, and never during the daytime.
Drow tend to be weaker and frailer than humans, but are better in most
other areas. Drow are somewhat resistant to magical attacks.

Class list:       Warrior, Cleric, Sorcerer, Conjurer, Necromancer, Thief,
                  Assassin, Bard, Reaver.
Innate abilities: levitate, faerie fire, ultravision, fireball, globe
                  of darkness, mass dispel.

Warning: As one of the eight evil races on Duris, the drow are extremely
difficult to play and face many hardships. Their hometown has been
specifically designed to make life hell and death waits around every
corner. Drow will most certainly encounter situations that would be deemed
&quot;unfair&quot; to any of the surface races. We did this to create a new challenge
for those advanced players who have &quot;beaten&quot; the challenge of life on the
surface world and are looking for something more difficult. You should NOT
play a drow unless you are a *very* advanced player and are used to the
Duris style of MUDding, or are willing to face the hardships without
complaint, as it will NOT be easy.
</content>
	<see-also file="greyelf"/>
	<see-also file="faeriefire"/>
	<see-also file="races"/>
</help-file>
