<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>DRUID</title>
	<category type="Sub-Class of: Priest"/>
<content>
Druids are powerful priestly types that concentrate their discipline toward
the betterment of nature and world preservation. They generally worship 
deities of the forest and of nature and will dispatch anyone attempting to 
desecrate or destroy a forest. Although their spell-like powers are 
primarily defensive in nature, they do command some very potent offensive 
magic once they attain the higher circles.

Druids have shunned the pantheon of gods and allied themselves with the 
natural world instead. They must 'commune' with their surroundings to 
derive the natural essence that is necessary for their spells. This essence
is most abundant in the untamed wilds.

The Druid class does not pray for spells like other &quot;priests&quot;, instead,
their spell slots refill automatically as long as they are not fighting,
casting, unconscious, etc. It is unnecessary to designate a specific array
of spells to memorize (see below). To offset this, the rate of spell 
recovery depends on the availability of natural essence in the Druid's 
surroundings. This essence is readily available in forests, but becomes 
more scarce on other types of terrain, especially indoors. Furthermore,
the essence is automatically channeled into the lowest circle that is not 
completely full before it is channeled into higher circles, so it is 
impossible to prioritize what spells to regain first. Overall, Druids have 
slower, more constant spell recovery.

Allowable races:        Human, Grey Elf, Half-Elf, Centaur

Innate abilities:       Shapechange, Charm Animal, Plane Shift

Equipment Usage:        Druids fall under the Priest classification of
                        item restriction. This means they are generally 
                        restricted to the use of non-edged weapons. Some 
                        exceptions are made depending on which deity the 
                        druid worships. They can wear almost all types of 
                        armor, and are only mildly restricted in usage of 
                        certain miscellaneous magical items.  
</content>
	<see-also file="skilldruid"/>
	<see-also file="commune"/>
</help-file>
