<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>GOBLIN</title>
<content>
Goblins are an inhospitable, evil race that prefers to dwell deep within
the depths of the Underdark. They live in a largely tribal society where
the strongest rule over the rest, existing preferably in underground caves
and similar dismal surroundings. Despite their primitive habitat they are a
rather clever and devious people that have mastered many of the same skills
and magics of the sun-loving races. Goblins are avid slavers and routinely
capture others to serve at their bidding, especially gnomes and mountain
dwarves whom they hate more than anything else.

Goblins range in appearance from a dark, dull green to a dull orange or
brick red. It is rumored that Goblins are distantly related to the Kobolds,
but to this day that claim has yet to be proven.

Class list:       Warrior, Cleric, Shaman, Sorcerer, Necromancer, Reaver,
                  Conjurer, Thief, Assassin, Mercenary, Bard, Alchemist,
                  Illusionist.
Statistics:       Goblins are a very intelligent people, therefore they
                  have become a feared race of proficient casters. They are
                  also quite nimble, making them naturals at stealing and
                  stealth.
Innate abilities: ultravision, flurry, disappear.

Warning: As one of the evil races on Duris, Goblins are extremely difficult
to play and face many hardships. Their hometown has been specifically
designed to make life hell and death waits around every corner. Goblins
will most certainly encounter situations that would be deemed &quot;unfair&quot; to
any of the surface races. We did this to create a new challenge for those
advanced players who have &quot;beaten&quot; the challenge of life on the surface
world and are looking for something more difficult. You should NOT play a
Goblin unless you are a *very* advanced player and are used to the Duris
style of MUDding, or are willing to face the hardships without complaint,
as it will NOT be easy.
</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="ultravision"/>
	<see-also file="infravision"/>
	<see-also file="innate"/>
</help-file>
