<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>"GOD, PARTICIPATION"</title>
<content>
This refers to the level to participation each god is expected to
contribute to the MUD. In order to obtain and maintain a god of some power
here on Duris, each god is expected to continually contribute in some
fashion.

The point the Forgers are trying to make is that it is a *privilege* to be
a god here on Duris, not a right. Once you have earned your immortality,
you are an example to all others below you, mortal or immortal, and there
will always be others that, given the chance, would gladly take your
position.

You are expected to contribute to the MUD in some fashion and on a regular
basis. Unlike some MUDs, you cannot create one or two zones, earn a god,
and ride on fame forever. We do NOT, however, mean that you have to work
every day (or even every month), but *some* type of contribution from every
god is necessary to keep Duris expanding and growing.

All gods will be assessed on a regular basis and assessments will be
handled in this manner:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Each month, during the Forgers' regular meeting, each god (including
forgers) will be evaluated for the month based on what they have done or
not done to contribute to the MUD. One month of inactivity is fine, even
two, if you are busy, but *not* three. If you have a reason, such as school
or something that inhibits you, fine. If you are having trouble to the
extent that it will drastically affect your MUD contribution, inform the
Forgers *immediately* and there will be no hassles whatsoever.

Bear in mind that gods with months of inactivity (without a plausible
excuse) will be demoted to mortal status. There will always be other people
who wish to work for Duris and help us out. Inactive gods can easily be
replaced.

The god slots are limited. Thus, if you wish to keep your god, you will
have to work for it like the rest of us (including Forgers).

Remember, it is a privilege to be a god here, not a right.
</content>
</help-file>
