<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>GROUP</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Syntax:  group &lt;playername&gt; (to add a member to your group)
         group me (to leave a group)
         group (to see who is currently in your group)

As you gain levels, you will find that a &quot;Group&quot; will be needed to progress
further in Duris. In order to form a group, first you must find other 
players to group with. Once you have all gotten together in one place and
are ready to go, a leader must be selected. All players must &quot;Consent&quot; the
leader to be part of the group by typing 'consent &lt;leadername&gt;'. The leader 
can now toggle group membership for each player by typing 
'group &lt;playername&gt;'. In addition, if all potential group members are 
following the group leader, he can type 'group all' to automatically group 
anyone following him who is not already grouped. When a person groups 
others, he is automatically included in the group as the group leader.

For example, Fizzwig and Oinkoink wish to form a group with Manwich.

Manwich toggles group membership by typing:
        group fizzwig
        group oinkoink

If Manwich types 'group fizzwig' after the group has been formed, Fizzwig 
will be kicked out of the group. If a group member, including the group 
leader, types 'group me', they will be removed from the group and the next 
player down the group list will automatically become the leader. Typing 
'group' with no argument will show you a list of people in the group and 
their condition.

Groups are comprised of the group leader and people in front and rear ranks.  
Type 'group &lt;playername&gt; front' to send a group member to the front ranks, 
and type 'group &lt;playername&gt; rear' to send a group member to the rear 
ranks.  Your position in the ranks determines how much damage you inflict 
(and receive) from spells and physical attacks.

Players that form a group still get the FULL amount of experience points 
when they kill a monster. This means there is no reason not to group with
another player if you only look at the experience factor. Everyone gets exp
regardless if they participate in the fight or not. In addition, frags are
divided among grouped players. 

If you find yourself in need of a group, you may implement the &quot;Group
Needed&quot; toggle.
</content>
	<see-also file="disband"/>
	<see-also file="experience"/>
	<see-also file="follow"/>
	<see-also file="gsay"/>
	<see-also file="consent"/>
	<see-also file="ranks"/>
	<see-also file="frag"/>
</help-file>
