<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>GUILDS ASSOCIATIONS CLANS</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
This document is designed to answer any questions regarding the creation
of player guilds on Duris. Under the current guild system players are
responsible for the organization of their own guilds. 
The gods themselves will not be responsible or serve any function in the
running of a guild.

How To Begin A Guild
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

a) The requirements for forming a guild are as follows :
    -All guild members must be at least 25th level or above. The level
      requirement is simply to ensure that the people in the guild are
      familiar with Duris and how it's run.
    -A guild may have upto, but no more than, 3 shared characters.
      These characters can be accessable by some/all members of the guild,
      but are not directly owned by anybody in the guild.
    -Guilds must also keep a member count of at least 5 members, 
      this 5 does <R>NOT</R> include the 3 shared characters.  The guild is
      also limited to a maximum of 35 members in the guild at a time.
    -A one time fee of 1,000 platinum is required to start the guild.
      This not does include a guildhall.

IMPORTANT
    -You may only have one character in a guild, and at most one alt in the
      <R>SAME GUILD</R>, at a time.  No exceptions.
    -You as a player can only secede from three different guilds EVER.
      If you leave your third different guild, that's it.
    -If you leave a guild you must wait one real week before joining
      another.
    -You may only kick out one member per mud month at a time.

b) What this allows -Once this happens the guild will be created and the
   person forming the guild will be flagged as a guild 'leader'. This will
   allow him/her to recruit members into the guild and promote/demote them
   accordingly. This is done completely without god interference and
   controlled by the code. Any new members will be automatically be flagged
   and titled as a member of the guild. This also will create a guild bank
   account which is accessible by Leaders and Deputies.
   Once a guild has been started and approved by Duris, the guild members
   of that guild must run their own activities. How many people there are
   of a certain guild rank is entirely up to the players. The gods
   themselves will have no interference with the running of the guild
   themselves. Any new members, once enrolled will automatically be titled
   as a basic member of that guild.

Guild Structure
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Guilds have specific ranks within them which give their members to ability
do different things depending on their rank. How this works is as follows :

Leader -A leader can change the names of all the ranks (this allows an
guild of sorcerers to name the leader as &quot;ArchMage&quot; rather than &quot;Leader&quot;.
These titles must be realistic in a <Y>fantasy world</Y>. A leader also has the
ability to flag a player as an enemy to the guild (leaders are the only
ones that can remove this flag as well). The leader can also add on an
'on parole' flag to members.

Deputy -A deputy (or higher) can delete, promote and demote members and
also has access to withdraw money from the guild's bank account.

Officer -An officer (or higher) has the right to fine lower members
(dealing out punishments etc).

Senior member -A senior member (or higher) has the right to enroll new
members.

Normal member -A Normal member just has general abilities, access to any
guildhalls that might be available etc. They can also see what other guild
members are online.

Enemy -The guild leader has the ability to flag a member as a guild enemy
as well. This will cause the guild npc's (if any) to attack the player on
sight and is used for betrayal etc.

Applying for Membership
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
In order to be allowed into a guild the player must first apply himself as
an applicant. You can do this by using the 'Society Apply &lt;member&gt;' command
where &lt;member&gt; is the enrolling member of the guild you wish to join.

Guild Locker
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
All guilds currently have a guild locker.  Go to any bank in a hometown
where you can access your personal locker, and you can access your guild
locker with <Y>enter locker guild</Y>.  All members share access to this
locker.  This replaces the need for guild chests in guildhalls.

</content>
	<see-also file="construct"/>
	<see-also file="society"/>
	<see-also file="guildhall"/>
	<see-also file="title"/>
</help-file>
