<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>HARPY GARGOYLE</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Harpies are a race of bird people that come from the jungle climates of 
Khomani-Khan. A matriarchal system governs their towns, where the females 
are usually more powerful and dangerous. They are usually frail in physical 
form, but quite adept at the mystical arts. Harpies are slender and 
humanoid, with large wings. The most vital fact of the Harpy species is 
their alliance with no single race, as they are borne into the world 
neutral. They must complete a quest to choose their destiny in the world of 
Duris. Indeed, the harpy culture breeds those who follow the path of 
darkness, light, and even undeath.

Class list:       Sorcerer, Conjurer, Ethermancer, Bard
Statistics:       Harpies are an aerial race that tend to be quick and
                  hearty, yet not very strong. They are much more suited to
                  magic than any combat classes. They regain their spell
                  slots via 'tupor', a calming-state. Due to their bird-
                  like nature, Harpies are constantly flying and have the 
                  ability to 'flutter' to avoid attack and their keen eyes 
                  can see farther than other races. Harpies cannot wear 
                  equipment on their feet or legs, yet they may wear horns.
Innate abilities: fly, perception, dayvision, ultravision
Strength:         Harpies are extremely agile and dexterous creatures with
                  hearty constitutions.
Weakness:         Harpies are usually considerably more frail than an
                  average human, though slightly stronger than elvenkind.
                  Due to their communion with the forces of wind and cold,
                  Harpies must be at least resting or even asleep in order
                  to tupor, thereby making them extremely prone to attack.
                  
</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="fly"/>
	<see-also file="perception"/>
	<see-also file="dayvision"/>
	<see-also file="tupor"/>
	<see-also file="flutter"/>
	<see-also file="ultravision"/>
</help-file>
