<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>JUSTICE</title>
<content>
Justice in hometowns when dealing with PKill/PSteal
DEFINITIONS:

PKill:  Player killing.  (as opposed to mob killing)

PSteal: Player stealing.  Stealing from, or attempting to steal from
        another player.
&quot;Aggro action&quot;:  For the purposes in this message, an 'aggro action'
                 is any form of physical or magical attack against
                 another player (attempted PKill), OR PSteal.

Outcast: Being outcast from a hometown means that if you set foot in
         that hometown, there is the danger of a specialized group of
         guards coming to kill you.

<R>NOTE</R>: ALL OTHER RACES EXCEPT ELF AND HALF-ELF ARE CONSIDERED INVADERS
           TO CHARING, AND WILL BE HUNTED DOWN AND KILLED ON SITE!

HOW JUSTICE WORKS:

JUSTICE ONLY APPLIES IN GOOD ALIGNED HOMETOWNS!

-Any player that witnesses a crime in a hometown can report it to the
  justice.
-If you commit a crime within a hometown and a citizen sees you he/she will
  report it to the justice.
-When a crime is reported to the justice, guards will be sent to arrest the
  criminal (if he/she is still in town).

If a guard arrests you, you will be brought to jail and you will be judged
for your crime during the next justice session.
The sentence you get will depend on the crime you committed.
In each hometown there is a justice hall. The following commands are
available there :

Reporting a crime
  reporting &lt;attacker&gt; &lt;crime&gt; &lt;victim&gt;
Pardoning someone for a crime against you
  pardon &lt;name&gt;
Pay a dept to the town
  pay
List all wanted criminals (see below)
  list
Turn in a wanted criminal
  turn_in &lt;name&gt;

The list of supported crime is :
  Att_theft   (attempted theft)
  Theft       (theft)
  Att_murder  (attempted murder)
  Murder      (murder)

Wanted criminal
  Each hometown has a list of wanted criminals with the reward for bringing
him in. If you catch a wanted criminal and bring him to justice you will get
a reward for it. There is a new command &quot;BIND&quot; that you can use to bring a
live criminal in.

Nothing prevents you from escaping jail, but if you do you will pay the price.

<R>IMPORTANT</R>
-Pardoning a person for a crime against you does not prevent this person from
  going to jail but it will be used by the judge when he gives his/her
  sentence.
-You cannot report a murder against yourself. 
-If someone commits a crime against you, you are not allowed to attack him, 
  let justice take care of it.
-A witnessed event is erased after a month, so dont wait too long to report a 
  crime.
</content>
	<see-also file="rules"/>
	<see-also file="laws"/>
	<see-also file="outcast"/>
	<see-also file="pkill"/>
	<see-also file="steal"/>
	<see-also file="bind"/>
</help-file>
