<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>LAWS RULES</title>
<content>
Read these carefully and fully ignorance is no excuse.

1.   Player killing is expected to be fully used by all! If someone,
     pisses you off, kill their ass and loot their corpse!

2.   <R>Multi-playing is NOT allowed</R>. For clarification of
     multi-playing, <Y>see &quot;help multi-playing.&quot;</Y>

3.   Bugs are to be reported to gods ASAP. Since we constantly put in 
     new code, there are bound to be bugs. If you aren't sure if 
     something is a bug, ask a god.

4.   Players should settle their own disputes. Talking to a god
     should be a last resort, as gods abide by the non-interference 
     policy. Use the petition channel if you need to consult with a god.

5.   Running robots in ANY shape or form is illegal. This means any robot
     that you set up with clients such as Tintin.

6.   Don't do anything the gods would consider cheesy.                     

                        <B>DURIS BUG POLICY</B>

You must report all bugs you as a player find on Duris using the boards,
however once you have reported this bug you <g>MAY NOT</g> use it as many
times as you like till the code no longer allows you to.  There is no
exception to this rule. Any bug you find that <R>CRASHES</R> or <R>FREEZES</R>
the mud must be reported immediately after the next time you login and never
used again.

We the operators of Duris Diku have played many muds over the years and
have always believed that if the code lets you it is for lack of a better term
an undocumented feature of that mud.  We will <y>NOT</y> delete players who show
exceptional mudding ability and find these little gems or we might end up
possibly losing the best players on the mud.

Now you may be telling yourself well gee I'll just use a bug over and over
then the first time a god sees me I will tell them I just found it.  Well my
friends <R>THIS WILL NOT WORK</R> because if we see you use a bug once we wont
say anything and will wait for you to either post about it or for you to
use the bug again if it has not already been fixed.

What happens if you use a bug over and over again and don't report it?  As
stated before you will not be deleted however you are subject to penalties
deemed appropriate by the gods at the time, which could be anything from 
a loud chewing out to losing all of your equipment.

If you don't like these rules, too bad, we do and we own the damn machine.
</content>
	<see-also file="multiplaying"/>
	<see-also file="racewars"/>
	<see-also file="robots"/>
	<see-also file="raid"/>
</help-file>
