<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>LOCKER STORAGE</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Syntax:         enter locker &lt;name&gt; 
		
Lockers can be found throughout the hometowns of the various races. Lockers 
are personal storage areas where spare equipment that has accumulated can 
be placed. There are various levels of locker access. 

To access your personal locker, type 'enter locker' at any local bank. 

To enter the locker of another person, they must have granted you access. 
You can enter someone else's locker, type 'enter locker char_name'. 

To enter a communal guild locker, you must type 'enter locker guild'. You 
must be a member of the guild to enter! Only one person is allowed in any 
locker, including guild lockers, at any one time. 

The Storage Locker Safety Commission, a group of other-world agents 
summoned by the immortals of this realm, have been called forth to guard 
these magical lockers from unauthorized intrusion. They are responsible 
for the protection of these lockers -any illegal entry or attempts at 
subterfuge will be punished. 

Anything you drop in a locker room will be stored and saved as if you were 
carrying it on your person and rented. This means items that are transient
will crumble and items flagged no rent will disappear. Anyone who is on 
your grant list will be able to access your locker as well. Please see 
&quot;help grant&quot; for information on giving others access to your locker!

To help with sorting and finding eq stored in a locker the command &quot;quit 
sort&quot; can be used. Typing that while in the locker will show a long list 
of options to sort eq by. If the player proceeds to sort eq by one of 
those stats it will place all items that have this stat in another chest 
inside the locker, 2.chest.

Example:
syntax: equip sort wis_max

This will place all items that have the max_wis stat in 2.chest.
</content>
	<see-also file="banks"/>
	<see-also file="grant"/>
</help-file>
