<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>MINOTAUR</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Minotaur are a half bull, half human race, with the torso of a man, and the
head and legs and feet of a bull. Huge horns protrude from the head.
Minotaur are one of the neutral races of Duris, and as such can pick which
side of the race war they will be on at birth.

Class list:       Warrior, Mercenary, Shaman.
Statistics:       Minotaur are a very powerful race and have both great
                  strength, hearty constitution. Being half bull, they are
                  stronger then any race other then ogres or storm giants.
                  They can see in both day and night with their amazing
                  eyesight, and they can withstand a large amount of 
                  damage. Despite their bad tempers, honor and pride are
                  ALL to a Minotaur.
Weakness:         Minotaurs lose their temper often, being partly bulls,
                  and not quite being able to ignore that aspect of their
                  nature, whenever a Minotuar loses more then 50% of his hit 
                  points, he will become enraged with bloodlust and attack
                  anything in his path, friend and foe alike! Minotaur have
                  VERY large legs, and thus can not wear anything on them,
                  and their hoof-like feet, prevent them from wearing
                  anything on them as well. Also, due to their huge horns
                  they can not wear anything on their heads. They have been
                  known however, to wear things on their horns, and
                  sometimes things in their large noses, or on their tail.                  
Innate abilities: infravision, ultravision, doorbash, bodyslam, charge

</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="infravision"/>
	<see-also file="ultravision"/>
	<see-also file="charge"/>
	<see-also file="bodyslam"/>
	<see-also file="doorbash"/>
</help-file>
