<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>"MULTI-CLASS" MULTICLASS</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Upon reaching level 50, you may &quot;multi-class&quot; your character, meaning to
add a second class choice to your character. This is not without its drawbacks
however. Also, once you multi-class you CANNOT later change your choice if you
do not like it.

Here are some things to first consider. First you can only multi into classes
that are offered by your race. Some combinations are not available so using 
the command 'multi' on your character will tell you which combinations ARE
available. Multiclasses will get the worst of both classes. All classes have 
dam mod and pulse bonuses/drawbacks. Casters tend to get dam mod penalties. If 
you multi between a hitter and caster the combo would get the casters dam mod, 
pulse and hp. If you multiclass with a class that has fewer slots than other 
casters (such as a bard) the multiclass will the same number of slots as the 
class with the least. A cleric/bard would get bard slots.

The spells/skills of the secondary class are ALL moved up 5 levels. This means  
if a secondary class got a skill at level 51 it will be moved up to 56. This 
means  the multiclass will never be able to gain the 51 skills/spells of the 
secondary class. This because multiclasses will be capped at level 55 or 
lower.

Multiclasses will only be able to wear the eq the prime class can wear. This 
goes for all types of eq, arti as well as normal. Let me repeat that. You 
can ONLY use artifacts that your prime class can use.

The maximum level you can go up to as a multi-class will be 55. Your second
class will always be -5. So at 55 the highest your second class will recognize
is 50. Also, when you multi you lose your specialization you had and go back 
to level 1, with level 1 hitpoints.  Here are the options available to each 
class &quot;IF ALLOWED BY YOUR RACE&quot;. Also, for sake of balance, some  
combinations are not allowed (and not on the list of course).

-Cleric: Warrior, Druid, Shaman
-Bard: Sorcerer, Rogue
-Sorcerer: Conjurer
-Warrior: Cleric, Mercenary
-Ranger: Warrior, Druid
-Anti-Paladin: Warrior
-Paladin: Warrior
-Druid: Shaman, Cleric
-Shaman: Conjurer, Druid, Cleric, Reaver
-Mercenary: Rogue, Warrior
-Rogue: Bard, Mercenary
-Reaver: Shaman
-Conjurer: Shaman, Sorcerer

Multi-Class Names
</content>
</help-file>
