<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>MULTI-PLAYING MULTIPLAYING MULTI</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Multi-playing, as defined by the gods of Duris, is the playing of more than
one character at a time by any one person, or the sharing of any one
character by two people.

1) You may NOT have more than one character on at ANY time. THIS INCLUDES
   LINK-DEAD CHARACTERS. You MUST rent or camp out your other character
   BEFORE you bring on a new one. The ONLY exception to this is rule #4.

2) You may NOT bring on another character for the purpose of using it to
   act as a &quot;translator&quot; to get around the language barrier.

3) You may NOT bring on another character in order to retrieve 
   equipment, or facilitate the retrieval of equipment for a character
   that has died, REGARDLESS of whether that other character's corpse has
   decomposed or not. This includes, but is not limited to, creating 
   &quot;newbies&quot; to retrieve help retrieve corpses or eq REGARDLESS of who's  
   corpse is being retrieved.  

4) You may NOT have two or more characters online in any way, shape or
   form, UNLESS you are exchanging equipment or using a storage character.
   Multiple characters may only be online inside an inn, and the inn is
   ONLY the one room that you use to rent in and out. Rooms that are
   adjacent to the inn room are NOT acceptable places to have 2 or more
   characters logged in at the same time.

5) You may NOT use a second character to cast spells on another. This rule
   also applies to logging another character on as a &quot;target&quot; for a spell.
   As well, you may not use a second &quot;newbie&quot; character for the purpose
   of creating &quot;newbie equipment&quot; for another character.

6) You may NOT use a second character with the sole purpose being to camp
   near an equipment repop site. Despite the importance of equipment,
   hoarding equipment by this means is deplorable, dishonorable, and 
   ILLEGAL.  It is also illegal to have a character log in the game for 
   the sole purpose of being a target for etherportal, moonwell, relocate, 
   or other methods of long distance travel. This also includes cases 
   where someone else is playing/controlling the &quot;camped 'port target.&quot;

7) You may <r>NOT</r> bring on a character of an opposite race and use that 
   char to gain information and then pass it along to another of your 
   characters who are on the other side of the race war. Example: Madra is
   a Gnome and has gone with her party of high level good race pc's into
   the underdark on a raid. While there, she gets separated from her party
   and is almost killed by a group of Drow and Duergar, so she goes and
   camps until they leave. She then logs on a newbie Drow and goes to check
   the area she rented at to find out when the group that was after her has
   left. And then she logs on another good race PC and passes on that
   information she got with her newbie Drow to her main party, thus giving
   them information they would NOT have. This goes for high level chars of
   the same race too.

   If Madra happened to have a high level Duergar and only logged on that  
   char to get information as to the location of the people after her other 
   char, she would be considered multi-playing and ALL her chars would be 
   deleted. This goes for evil pc's doing the same thing as the example 
   above.

   <R>YOU MUST WAIT 1 HOUR BEFORE LOGGING IN A CHARACTER ON THE OTHER SIDE
   </R><R>OF THE RACEWARS</R>

   This also goes for people who log on other side chars just to see who 
   is on. Now, we KNOW this rule will be hard to enforce and we WON'T be 
   able to catch everyone who does it. But rest assured, that when we DO 
   catch you, your ass WILL be deleted right there on the spot NO questions 
   asked.

8) You may <R>NOT</R> log on another character to take revenge for another of
   your characters that was just killed or assist in anyway in taking
   revenge until at least 1 RL hour has passed. If you do this and get 
   caught you WILL be deleted on the spot. This includes knowingly going
   back to an area where you might reasonably expect to come back into
   the same racewar contact you have just left with the first character.

   Example1: Joe2 is Joe1's secondary. Joe2 is leveling just fine until 
   another PC named Jeff walks into the room and kills Joe2. Shortly after
   Jeff is done looting Joe2, Joe1 logs back on and moonwells himself and a
   big party in to kill Jeff and get Joe2's eq back.   

   Example2: An illithid hears that someone is attacking its primarys'
   guild hall. It worms in, attacks the people trying to get into guild and
   dies many times. So it rents, and after less then 15 mins has passed he
   logs on his primary character to join a group that is defending the
   guildhall.
   
   So play it smart and don't risk it. Most often there IS a high level god 
   on who IS watching, especially if there is a raid going on.

If you require clarification of these rules, <R>ASK A GOD</R>.

Anyone caught multi-playing will be *severely* dealt with.

As an example ONLY: For a first offense you may lose ONE HALF of your
levels. For a second offense, you will be DELETED. This is ONLY an example;
the actual punishment is up to the god on at the time and is NOT a
debatable issue.

If you have *any* questions on what exactly constitutes multi-playing, post
it or ask the Gods with a petition. Chances are it's a no-no.  These
guidelines, as with all rules, are subject to the interpretation of the Gods!
</content>
	<see-also file="laws"/>
	<see-also file="rules"/>
	<see-also file="rent"/>
	<see-also file="languages"/>
</help-file>
