<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>NEWBIE</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
The term &quot;newbie&quot; is given to a player who is new to the MUD or to MUDding
in general. If you fit this category, we suggest that you spend some time
reading the help files. This will allow you to enter the game and play with
some degree of confidence.

Newbies are encouraged to ask questions of their fellow adventurers often,
to group for protection and to read thoroughly the HELP and INFO files for
information on the MUD.

MUD is an acronym for &quot;multi-user dungeon&quot;.  Although there are different
types of MUDs all over the world, Duris runs on modified UBC code and is
loosely based on the Forgotten Realms series of AD&amp;D (Advanced Dungeons and
Dragons) products from TSR, Inc.

NEWBIE TIPS:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
If you are new to Duris and the Duris style of MUDding, there are some tips
you can follow that can help you get better oriented and give you more
control over the way you see the world.

First and most importantly, Duris can be a very difficult world, and if you
are not an advanced player it is HIGHLY recommended you play a good raced
character rather than an evil one. Evils face many hardships of various
kinds, and in general evils do not take kindly upon strangers.

Some commands that will help you further: 

<W>1. READ 'HELP COMMANDS'</W>. 
This will list all the basic commands you will need to act and interact 
within the MUD. Spend time experimenting with the commands until you feel 
confident using them.

<W>2. TOGGLES</W>. 
Typing 'toggle' will give you a list of personal settings you can switch 
on and off for your character. These toggles affect elements such as what 
your character sees, how it communicates, how it behaves in combat and 
much more. Make sure you read 'HELP TOGGLE' for more in-depth info mation 
on individual toggles.

<W>3. DISPLAY</W>. 
Typing 'help display' will give you a list of display commands. Experiment 
with these commands until you are familiar with how each one affects what 
you see while playing. After your character first enters the game, we 
strongly recommend typing 'DISPLAY ALL'. This should make things easier on 
you.

If you require any further help, ask your fellow adventurers or check out
the Duris website. Try to group with those near your level to do experience, 
if you are a good raced character you are able to use &quot;nchat&quot; (newbie chat 
channel) to ask questions, or petition a god for help if you're truly lost.
</content>
	<see-also file="toggle"/>
	<see-also file="display"/>
	<see-also file="commands"/>
	<see-also file="website"/>
	<see-also file="forums"/>
	<see-also file="index"/>
	<see-also file="nchat"/>
</help-file>
