<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>NEW-COMBAT "NEW COMBAT" "GROUP RANKS" RANKS "FRONT RANK" "BACK RANK"</title>
<content>
The biggest, most important change with the new combat stuff is the
new, increased importance of group ranks.  Group ranking is now critical
to the success of PvP engagements.

As before, there are two group ranks ... front and back.  However, the
old effects of group ranking are no longer.

  *)  You must have, at all times, more people in the front rank of your
      group than in the back rank.  The code will enforce this for the
      most part, though there will be times (especially when someone dies
      or leaves the room) when it won't immediately be updated.

  *)  If you are in the rear rank, leave the room, and come back in, as with
      a flee/return combo, you will automatically be ranked to the front.

  *)  Targeted spells can be targeted by anyone on anyone, regardless of
      which group rank the caster and target are in.

  *)  Area spells are still in the game, with a few modifications:
	-Casting time has been increased for all areas
	-Area spells do significantly less damage than before
	-Area spells hit ALL ranks in front of you.  This means if you are
	  grouped to the back rank, you will hit your front rank as well as
	  both enemy ranks.  If you are ranked front, you will hit only the
	  enemy group.

  *)  People in the rear ranks are much harder to target with physical
      attacks. 

The general theory behind this change is to change battles from the current
area spam-fests to battles that require thought and skill to win.  Clearly a
basic group format will have tanks and hitters in the front ranks, with clerics
and other casters in the rear ranks.  However, experimentation with various
group formats will be critical to success.  There will also be no single one
size fits all solution that guarantees a win ... you will have to be flexible
and above all, you have to use your brain, especially with who the primary
targets will be for both casters as well as hitters.

Remember, once you kill one of the front ranked people, one of the rear ranked
guys moves forward (assuming equal numbers in front and back)

I'll leave it up to you folks to see how mob combat will be affected by these
changes.

Expect damages, spell chant times, and just about any other facet of this to
be tweaked as it's used.  Of great use to me will be battle logs that show
problems you may run across.  
</content>
</help-file>
