<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>ORC</title>
<content>
Orcs are a race of evil humanoids that are, typically, five feet tall with
green or yellowish skin and red eyes. Orcs tend to be more social then most
other evil races, preferring to group with as many of their fellows as
possible. Orcs, while preferring the company of other orcs, are known to
also group with Ogres and Trolls, and even Drow and Duergar from time to
time. Orcs are some of the most deadly creatures to be found on Duris.

Class list:	  Warrior, Anti-Paladin, Cleric, Shaman, Sorcerer, Reaver,
		  Necromancer, Thief, Assassin, Mercenary, Bard, Alchemist,
		  Berserker, Illusionist, Conjurer.
Statistics:       Orcs tend to be weaker then most other races, but make up
                  for that weakness by the sheer force of numbers, and 
                  their unique vision, which allows them to see in both
                  darkness and light, allowing them to be the only race on
                  all of duris to travel both the lands of light and dark.
Innate Abilities: Infravision, Ultravision, Summon Horde.

<R>Warning</R>: As one of the eight evil races on Duris, orcs are
extremely difficult to play and face many hardships.  Their hometown
has been specifically designed to make life hell, and death waits
around every corner.  Orcs will most certainly encounter situations
that would be deemed &quot;unfair&quot; to any of the good races.  We did
this to create a new challenge for those advanced players who have
&quot;beaten&quot; the challenge of life on the surface world, and are looking
for something more difficult.  You should NOT play an orc unless you
are a *very* advanced player and are used to the Duris style of
MUDding, or are willing to face the hardships without complaint, as it
is NOT easy.
</content>
	<see-also file="summonhorde"/>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="innate"/>
	<see-also file="ultravision"/>
	<see-also file="infravision"/>
</help-file>
