<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>RACEWARS PKILL PLAYERKILL</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Duris consists of a delicately balanced  To make these wars possible, 
player-killing (aka pkill) is tolerated and even encouraged, subject to 
rules described below.

The good races consist of (Grey Elves, Mountain Dwarves, Gnomes, Halflings, 
Centaurs, Barbarians, Half-Elves and Humans). Undead races include 
(Vampires, Liches, Wights, Shadow Beasts, Death Knights, Phantoms, 
Revenants and Shades). Evil races are (Drow Elves, Duergar Dwarves, Swamp 
Trolls, Ogres, Orcs, Goblins and Githyankis). Alltogether, there are three 
neutral races in the Land of Duris, (Minotaurs, Thri-Kreens and Harpies). 
Minotaurs and Thri-Kreens may choose either the good or e il side of the
racewar when rolling a character. But, Harpies all enter the world as a
neutral race until they complete a quest to seal their fate in Duris.

These sides are at constant war with one another, in an attempt to take
over all of Duris. Each race will have its own home city and the city's
inhabitants are aggressive to the races of the other side. For example, if 
you are a Grey Elf and try to enter Archdrathos (the city of the Drow
Elves) you will be attacked on sight by the drow mobs, guardians of the 
city and possibly drow players. The same holds true for ALL cities of the 
realms.  

Outside of those cities, however, is a dangerous place. You never know who 
or what will be waiting for you on the other side of the city walls.  You
will quickly find that traveling in groups is the best way to survive. As 
to who can attack who, anyone CAN attack anyone.

Evil and Undead races will have a much harder time on Duris than the Good 
races do. Most are blind on the surface world during the day, suffering
from the pureness of daylight. Furthermore, life will be cruel and harsh on 
them. It will be substantially more difficult for ANYONE of an evil or 
undead race to make it to a high level, let alone reach the surface and 
kill anyone. As you can see, there will be plenty of ordeals for these 
races to overcome before they will have the chance to prey on others.
In addition, ANY evil-raced person on the surface will be hunted down by 
powerful good-raced PC's and killed on sight.

This is a VERY brief description of how race wars work on Duris.  The 
more intricate details will be revealed as they unfold.
</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
</help-file>
