<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>RAID</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
If you are trying to retrieve your corpse/EQ after dying in PvP combat you
CANNOT return unless you are fully re-equipped as outlined below.

If are trying to retrieve your corpse/EQ regardless of how you died and
encounter members of the opposite race, corpses from the opposite race or
have other information that members of the opposite race is in the zone you 
CANNOT return if you die again unless you are fully re-equipped as outlined 
below.

If you engage in PvP combat, you are <R>*required*</R> to be equipped in at 
least a minimal raid kit consisting of 12 items. To see if you are indeed
raidable you can use the command 'raid' and it will return a yes/no
statement. Included in PvP combat is casting spells on either friendly or 
foes while they are pvp'ing, looting corpses and scouting.

<Y>Punishment for raiding without the slots required is 1 level per
</Y><Y>missing slot plus the loss off all worn and looted. This applies 
</Y><Y>to all raiders. Cheat repeatedly and it will become harsher.

                        </Y><W>PLEASE READ THE REST:</W>

      Minor created and newbie start equipment is NOT acceptable, you must
   always wear your best equipment; if your best equipment is in your corpse,
      on the ground or in your imagination then you must use your next best.   

     Scouting and spam-looting with lowbie chars (like level one giths) is
         cheesy, and it pisses off the imms ... don't piss off the imms!

   If you are outside of your GH or Hometown, these rules are in full effect.
  So if an evil wants to exp in Wemics, or do Outcast Tower for EQ, he has to
    be in full raiding gear. If a goodie wants to exp in Smokeveil, the same
    applies as well as any other normal experience/zone/raid situation. The
      ONLY times you may bypass this are if your storage is in a different
      location than your pop spot (i.e. you pop in Ugta, your storage is in
    Tharnadia) or you are zoning to get equipment to become raidable. Using
    these to run around naked constantly, however, will result in our rapid
   termination from existence. Also, store-bought eq is fine ONLY if you have
      nothing better, either on storage or in your guild or house chests.
 
    LAKING your own equipment to prevent others from obtaining the equipment
      when you know you are going to die is cheesy and pisses off the Gods,
    don't piss off the Gods. This also contravenes the fact that you must be
                           wearing full raid slots.

    Thieves are now bound and held totally to the rules addressed above, as
                  well as the guidelines listed in Help Thief.
</content>
</help-file>
