<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>SHIP_CARGO</title>
<content>

Space
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Cargo takes up 1 unit of space on your ship. Sails take up 3 units of 
space, and each weapon takes up it's specific labeled amount of space. Type 
&quot;list&quot; to see how much space a weapon takes up. For every unit of cargo 
you are hauling, your ACTUAL top speed becomes 2 less than your LISTED top 
speed. This occurs ONLY if your ship is completely full(0 space remaining) 
This means if you are hauling 15 cargo, your actual top speed is 30 less 
than your listed top speed. You can still set your speed above this value, 
but your ship will not actually go that speed. See &quot;Help SHIP_LOOKS&quot; to 
see how to determine your current speed. Bigger ships have more space. 

Buying and Selling
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
To buy cargo, go to one of the major docks in the world, and dock your 
ship there. Then type &quot;list cargo&quot;. This gives you a list of the one type 
of cargo you can BUY at this dock, and the many other types of cargo you 
can SELL here. It also gives you a list of prices, which are vital to 
actually MAKING MONEY, which is the sole purpose of running cargo. Make 
sure you buy low and sell high. First determine how much space you have 
or need to make for cargo. A few methods of cargo running are: 

Minimum cargo, Maximum speed 
     (tune your ship to carry only enough cargo to travel 60-90) 
Half and half 
     (tune your ship to travel about 40-70 when hauling cargo) 
Maximum cargo, Minimum speed 
     (tune your ship to barely any sails or speed, but once you get there, 
      you'll be RICH -this is very hard without weapons -which take up 
      valuable cargo space) 

Finally, to buy cargo, stand on the dock, and type &quot;buy cargo #&quot; where # is 
the number of units of cargo you wish to buy. 

Once you buy the cargo, you sail to a DIFFERENT major dock.  Disembark, and 
type &quot;sell cargo&quot;. You should type &quot;list cargo&quot; to ensure you're making a 
profit first. 

Then, repeat, buy, sail somewhere, sell.... 

Next suggested reading: &quot;help SHIP_LOOKS&quot; 

Note: If you summon your ship to another location, all cargo in your ship 
will be lost. Use summon only as a last resort if you run cargo. 

Note: Each major docks has it's own type of cargo. This should never 
change. Therefore, by number of types of cargo available, you can determine
how many major ports there are, and even approximate what continent any
specific type of cargo can be purchased at. Example: Elven Goods are bought
on the Elven Continent. 

Note: A sloop and a Yacht have limited space. Those two ships can have 100%
sail, so you have to buy LESS than the max sail to haul cargo, at 3 sail
taking the same space as 1 cargo. 

Note: Many cargo ships have no weapons. If you are attacked, and you 
Would rather live and escape than sink to the bottom of the ocean, you can
type &quot;order jettison cargo&quot; and your actual top speed will now match your
listed top speed, allowing you to escape. 

</content>
	<see-also file="shipcommands"/>
	<see-also file="ships"/>
</help-file>
