<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>SHIP_COMBAT SHIP_BATTLE</title>
<content>
Combat on the ship system works on the principle of firing arcs, range, 
targets, and damage. 

Firing Arcs
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Firing arcs are the direction your weapons are pointing on your ship. For 
example, a ballistae mounted on your Port(Left) side is pointing to the 
ship's left, so if the target is on the right side, it is out of that 
particular weapon's arc, so if weapons are mounted only on the forward arc, 
that means the ship only has a limited arc of fire in the front. If a ship 
has weapons on all four parts of the ship it can shoot in any direction. 

Range
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Each weapon has a Short, Medium, and Long range to them. What this means 
is that a Large Ballistae which might have a Short range of 4, Medium of 
8, and long of 12 can shoot targets as far as 12 squares away, as the ship 
gets closer to the target and gets within 8 squares, the ship will have a 
better chance of hitting the target, if the target gets within 4 squares, 
it will be an almost sure hit. 

Targets
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Fighting in ships requires you to lock onto another ship. This uses the 
ID of the ship (covered in &quot;help Ship_Looks&quot;). The syntax is &quot;Lock &lt;ID&gt;&quot; 
When you are locked onto a ship, your crew will try to attack that ship and 
only that ship when you order them to fire weapons. However, you can 
reassign the Lock id at any time, as often and as quickly as you wish. 

Damage
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
When a ship is hit, it is hit on one of the four sides. Each side has 
two types of HP, armor and hull. Armor is made to take damage, as long as 
a ship has armor, its weapons and insides are protected. Once the ship's 
armor is blasted away however, damage goes to the hull of the ship. Hull 
is basically the framework of the ship, hits in the hull can cause critical 
hits where it knocks the crew to the ground or even destroys weapons. Once 
all the hull of a side is gone, the ship is taking on water, not enough to 
sink it, but enough to immobilize it. Once two hull sides are blown away, 
the ship no longer can float and will sink. If the ship is fast enough and 
doesn't want to get blown up, they have the choice of running, but be 
warned, the rear of a ship has about half the armor and has more delicate 
structure than the rest of the ship (Like the Rudder) so the ship will be 
quite vulnerable there. Also when a ship gets hit, it has a chance of 
getting hit in the sails which makes the ship not able to move as fast 
(can't move if your sails have big holes in it), and even possibly, with 
enough hits, the sail can get completely destroyed, making the ship 
immobile, or basically dead in the water -a sitting duck. 

Next suggested reading: &quot;help SHIP_CARGO&quot; 
If you don't like cargo: &quot;help SHIP_LOOKS&quot; 

Note: When a weapon is fired it will take approx 30 seconds to reload. 

Note: As a last resort you can RAM the other ship, which does massive 
damage to both.
Syntax:  Order Ram
You need to be moving fast for this to work.

Note: Many players will disembark their own ship after they immobilize 
yours, and then board yours to kill you AND your destroy your ship 
afterwards. You can also do this yourself (just don't die on THEIR ship).

After Sinking a ship, use the command &quot;Get Money&quot; to collect the prize
money for sinking your enemy.

</content>
	<see-also file="shiplooks"/>
	<see-also file="shipcommands"/>
	<see-also file="ships"/>
</help-file>
