<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>SHIP_LOOKS</title>
<content>

Look Out
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This command looks outside your ship, at the immediate surroundings. If 
you are in a dock zone, it will tell you the available exits much like when 
you are walking around normally. This will tell you other ships in your 
square, and it will show you a small portion of the worldmap (in squares) 
when you are outside. 

Look Tactical
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
look tactical (optional parameters are &lt;X&gt; &lt;Y&gt;) 

This will show you a tactical map centered on you (or x,y with 50,50 
being the center of the map -ie YOU). It is displayed as a hex grid and 
any nearby ships will be displayed according to their ID. The Hex grid is 
the square setup basically &quot;converted&quot; to a hex grid, so it is not always 
perfect in appearance. If the optional parameters &lt;X&gt; and &lt;Y&gt; are given the
map will center on that coord if it is within 35 hexes. This is a
calculated value, if you provide numbers outside the range, you will see an
error message. You cannot Look Tactical inside a dock zone. 

Look cargo
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This will tell you what cargo you currently have on your ship, and the 
price you paid for that cargo. 

Look Status/Look Ship
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This will show you a detailed status of your ship with HPs and weapon 
status (whether its reloading or ready to fire) and ammo remaining. It 
will also show your position, speed, heading and target. The ID number on 
the upper right corner of the status display is your current ID if you are 
sailing, or a ** if you are docked. This ID starts at AA for the first 
ship out, and continues for as many ships are currently sailing. It can be 
an indicator of how many other ships are sailing the world, also. 

Look Weaponspec
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This will show you the specifications of all your weapons. It will show 
their weapon ranges and damage each shot will do as well as if the weapon
is destroyed or not. 

Look Sight &lt;#&gt;
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This will show your percent chance to hit with a specific weapon.

Look Sight &lt;weapon number&gt; 
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
If your have a target this command will show you your percentage to hit
the current locked target with that particular weapon. 

Look Contacts
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This will display a list of all ships within a 35 square radius of your 
ship. This is the heart of getting info on your target. The list is broken 
into several parts and will look kinda like this:

Contact listing 
===============================================
[AN] 'NorgDog'         X:53  Y:50  Z:0   R:3.0   B:90  H:0   S:0 |S 

&quot;AN&quot; is the ship's ID this is the parameter you pass to lock to lock onto 
this target. 

'Norgdog' is the ship's name. 

X:53 and Y:50 are their x, y coords on your tactical map, so if you do a 
'look tactical 53 50', it will center the map on Norgdog. 

R:3.0 is Range, so in this case, Norgdog is 3 Squares from you. 

B:90 is their bearing to you, so in this case, Norgdog is to your east 
since 90 is east, so if you were to head east, you would be facing 
Norgdog. 

H:0 is Norgdog's heading.. so in this case, Norgdog is facing north 
since 0 is North. 

S:0 is Norgdog's speed so in this case, its not moving since it's 0. 

Last bit is the S, which means it is on your starboard firing 
arc, so if you have any weapons on your starboard side, they can fire at 
Norgdog. 

Next suggested reading: &quot;help SHIP_COMMANDS&quot; 

</content>
	<see-also file="shipcommands"/>
	<see-also file="ships"/>
</help-file>
