<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>SHIP_LIST</title>
<content>
This is one of few single commands that will be covered in a helpfile, 
simply because this command holds so much information. When you type 
&quot;list&quot; at a dock, after you have purchased a ship, you see 4 sections: 

-Hull Upgrades 
-Sail 
-Weapons 
-and then a set of sample commands. 


Hull Upgrades
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This section tells you all the larger ship classes you can upgrade your 
current ship to. A portion of the cost of your current hull will be 
deducted from the cost of upgrading to a higher hull class. This means, 
if you buy a sloop, and then a clipper, it will be more expensive than 
simply buying a clipper to start with. However, it will not be as costly 
as buying two separate ships (the clipper and the sloop). Again, you will 
not need to restate the name of your ship, when you upgrade your hull. 

Sail
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Your ship requires a sail to move (sorry, you cannot move a galleon by 
paddling it with your hands). Sails are free, but depending on the size of 
the sail, it can take a long time to make the sail and put it on the ship. 
If you do not have enough sail, your ship is immobile (your sail isn't very 
effective with big holes in it). Likewise, if your sail is damaged, you 
will move slower and slower until you are also immobile. 

Weapons
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Weapons are the fun part of sailing. Shooting down other players and 
their ships! Combat will be covered in &quot;Help SHIP_COMBAT.&quot; When you buy a
weapon, you must state what part of the ship the weapon should be mounted
on. You should read &quot;Help SHIP_COMBAT&quot; before you buy weapons, so you can
develop your fighting strategy and buy your weapons to match. To buy a
weapon, you type &quot;buy weapon # &lt;location&gt;&quot; where # is the weapon ID number
when you type &quot;list&quot; at the docks, and location is the part of the ship you
wish to place the weapon. 

At the moment, capitol weapons require 2000 ship frags to purchase.

Finally, the commands list at the bottom of the &quot;list&quot; command output a few 
commands on how to operate the buying, selling, repairing, reloading, etc. 
of your ship. There is also a line &quot;Available space on ship:&quot; which tells 
you how much space you have to purchase more cargo, sail, or weapons. The 
higher the ship class, generally means you have more room for each of these 
items. 

Next suggested reading: &quot;help SHIP_MOVEMENT&quot; 

</content>
	<see-also file="shipcombat"/>
	<see-also file="shipcommands"/>
	<see-also file="ships"/>
</help-file>
