<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>SHIP_MOVEMENT</title>
<content>
Once you have purchased your ship and sail, you are ready to sail the seas,
pillage ships, run cargo, and travel the world. 

Dock Movement
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
When you are docked, you cannot unfurl your sails and take off safely. 
You must first maneuver out to the open seas, away from the docks. Some 
docks have complex zones, much like a normal zone, except it's all water. 
You still maneuver in &quot;rooms&quot; dictating N,S,E, or W as the direction. 

The command to maneuver is: &quot;Order Maneuver &lt;direction&gt;&quot; 

World Movement
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
The ship system works on a principle of speed and heading. What this means
is, if you set your ship to a certain speed, it will continue moving until
the speed is set to 0. Heading is the direction that the ship is pointing
and hence will be the direction the ship will be traveling. Heading is
done from a 0-360 degree circle with north being 0, east being 90, south 
being 180, and west being 270. 

Also affecting the ships is acceleration and turn rate. When a speed is 
set, the ship does not immediately jump to that speed, it has to accelerate 
to the set speed. Acceleration is faster on smaller ships with large sails 
than a large ship with small sails. On the same note, when a heading is 
set, the ship does not immediately face that direction, it has to turn to 
indicated direction, this is the turn rate. Turn rate is higher on smaller 
ships than large Dreadnaughts, so theoretically a small fast Clipper can 
run circles around a Galleon. Turn rate is also affected by the speed of 
the ship, the faster a ship is traveling the slower they turn, and below a 
minimum speed, the ship also turns slower so it is best to maintain a 
medium speed for best maneuverability. 

Details
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
In order to re-dock your ship, you must be adjacent to the dock zone, or 
adjacent to an area of land which is dockable [Note-1], and you again use 
the &quot;order maneuver &lt;direction&gt;&quot; command as you use when you are leaving 
the docks. Beware: if you attempt to SAIL into a shore, you have a chance 
of CRASHING into the shore, even if the zone is a dock. Your ship crew 
will try to prevent this, but they cannot be relied upon every time.  You 
must also be traveling at 20 speed or less in order to attempt to maneuver. 

Next suggested reading: &quot;help Ship_Combat&quot; 

NOTE:  Such as shores and coasts. Not all shores and coasts are dockable 
You are expected to find these other locations yourself, however if another
ship is already docked there, this is a good indicator. To test a spot,
simply sail alongside the square, slow to 10 speed or less, and attempt to
maneuver onto the shore. If it works, you found it, if not, DON'T CRASH! :) 
         
</content>
	<see-also file="shipcommnds"/>
	<see-also file="ships"/>
</help-file>
