<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>SOCIETY</title>
<content>
Association Command

Syntax:   society &lt;s&gt;ubcommands argumentlist

(Subcommands can be accessed by just using the first letter.)


List of subcommands
-------------------

<W>society</W>
soc -displays a list of members and various info about them depending
      on your rank. Members higher in rank than you are only shown if online.
      Also displays some info on the association to higher ranks.
      Finally it gives a list of people ostracized by your association.

<W>society apply member</W>
soc a Hero -applies to the (senior or higher) member Hero of an association
             for membership in his association.
soc a me -clears an existing application to an association.

<W>society enroll applicant</W>
soc e Newone -enrolls Newone to the association, if he has applied for
               membership first.

<W>society kickout member</W>
soc k Twink -kicks member Twink out of the association, erasing his name
              in the member list. Is also used to delete names from the
              ostracism list.

<W>society secede [confirm]</W>
soc s -just displays a warning message that &quot;soc s confirm&quot; has to be typed
soc s confirm -the member leaves the association. All his data is erased
                from the member list -except if he was a declared enemy.
                Then he is automatically put on the ostracism list.

<W>society ostracize name</W>
soc o Anti -puts the name &quot;Anti&quot; on the ostracism list. The association's
             guards will then attack any person with the name &quot;Anti&quot; as
             if they had the rank enemy in the association.

<W>society rank name change</W>
soc r Lucky 2 -the member Lucky is promoted by two ranks.
soc r Noluck -3 -the member Noluck is demoted by three ranks.
                   Note that the minimum mortal rank obtainable with this
                   normal (member) and the maximum is leader.

<W>society punish name</W>
soc p Arrggh -the first punish puts member Arrggh on parole.
soc p Arrggh -the second one declares Arrggh as enemy, thus making the
               association guards aggressive to him. The rank subcommand
               (see above) can be used to reinstate Arrggh, but only a
               leader can do this once he is of enemy rank.

<W>society challenge member</W>
soc c Bigger -(this is not allowed by all association) this challenges a
               member of the next higher rank for his position. This is
               a political command, there is no auto-attack. The outcome
               of the challenge depends mainly on experience and the
               looser faces tough penalties.

<W>society name rank_keyword new_rank_name</W>
soc n enemy Hunted by -the new rank name of the enemy rank is &quot;Hunted by&quot;.
                        A list of rank_keywords and current names for them
                        is shown to the leader with the &quot;soc&quot; list.
soc n l Master of -the rank keywords can be abbreviated as well, here &quot;l&quot;
                    stands for leader rank, now called &quot;Master of&quot;.
soc n normal -without a new rank name, the rank name is wiped and in the
               title only the association name is shown.
               ANSI can be used in rank names. Note that the association name
               is pasted directly behind the rank name, so often a trailing
               space is necessary in the given rank name.

<W>society home</W>
soc h -set your hometown and birthplace to your guild hall. You must be 
        inside your hall for it to work.

* The following money commands accept multiple arguments for &quot;money&quot; and
* the coin type is determined by the first letter only. So a valid
* example would be: &quot;10 plat 2 gc 3 s 5 copper&quot;.

<W>society fine name money</W>
soc f Wrong 20 p 10 sc -issues a fine of 20 platinum and 10 silver coins to
                         member Wrong of the association.
soc f Wrong -30 plat -subtracts 30 plat from the debt Wrong has. If he has
                       less than 30 p debts, then his debt is set to zero.
soc f all 20 gold -issues a fine of 20 gold (for example as membership fee)
                    to everybody. Note that one can fine only lower ranks, so
                    in truth this would give only fines to all lower ranks.

<W>society deposit money</W>
soc d 12 platinum 30 cc -deposits 12 plat and 30 copper into the association
                          account. Any debts the member has are lessened
                          accordingly. This subcommand can be used by
                          applicants to pay an entrance fee.

<W>society withdraw money</W>
soc w 100 plat -withdraws 100 platinum coins from the association account.

<W>society title name new_title</W>
soc t billybob <Y>Corn</Y><W>Husker </W><C>Supreme</C> -sets BillyBob's 'rank'
title to CornHusker Supreme.  this title is never overwritten by new
rank titles as long as the &quot;no title change&quot; toggle is set (see below).
this command can only be used by guild leaders (to title other players),
or deputies and officers (to title themselves).

<W>society toggle_title_flag</W>
soc g -toggles your 'no title change' flag
</content>
	<see-also file="societyexamples"/>
	<see-also file="construct"/>
	<see-also file="guild"/>
	<see-also file="guildhall"/>
</help-file>
