<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>TROLL "SWAMP TROLL"</title>
<content>
Swamp trolls are a huge, massive, evil, and disgusting species that are
greatly feared by all races. They are often hunted by humans, and are 
easily identifiable by their decided lack of intelligence, green hair, and 
pale-green, horned and slimy skin. Trolls' strength is horrifying and, 
since they are destructive by nature, they customarily spend all of their 
time killing and destroying. Trolls also frequently raid towns in order to 
procure slaves that become the &quot;guests of honor&quot; at future feasts. Trolls 
live in hot swamps and lakes, and generally band together in clans. Their 
only contact with other races occurs during acts of war. Trolls regenerate 
faster than other races do, and possess innate ultravision.

Class list:       Warrior, Shaman, Mercenary.
Statistics:       Quite strong, tall and thin, very quick, also regen hit
                  points at a truly amazing rate, however, they are almost
                  as stupid as ogres, just about as ugly too. Only what
                  passes as a genius for a troll will do well as a shaman.
Innate abilities: ultravision, bodyslam (warrior only), doorbash,
                  regeneration

<R>Warning:</R>  As one of the eight evil races on Duris, trolls are
extremely difficult to play and face many hardships.  Their hometown
has been specifically designed to make life hell, and death waits
around every corner.  Trolls will most certainly encounter situations
that would be deemed &quot;unfair&quot; to any of the surface races.  We did
this to create a new challenge for those advances players who have
&quot;beaten&quot; the challenge of life on the surface world and are looking
for something more difficult.  You should NOT play a troll unless you
are a *very* advanced player and are used to the Duris style of
MUDding, or are willing to face the hardships without complaint, as it
is NOT easy.

<R>NOTE</R>:  Trolls are extremely vulnerable to all fire-based spells
            and will take more damage from them.

</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="racewars"/>
	<see-also file="innate"/>
	<see-also file="infravision"/>
	<see-also file="bodyslam"/>
</help-file>
