<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>THARNADIA</title>
<content>
The sprawling metropolis of Tharnadia is the most active city in all of
Duris. It is the cornerstone of the human economy and the jewel of their
empire. Tharnadia can be found in the southwest corner of the continent,
nestled against its broad and busy port.

Perhaps the most popular place to congregate in Tharnadia is the Ogre's 
Foot Inn. The inn is located roughly in the center of the city, directly in
front of the city's constantly-bubbling fountain. To the west of the Inn 
you will find the city's resident cleric-physician, who will tend to your 
wounds for a small fee. Further west are the stairs to the Shr'nn Mesa, 
which leads to the city's prison -Caer Tannad. Upon further exploration
you'll be happy to find many guild towers complete with shops and teachers,
and also the main cargo port for Tharnadia lies here. The northenmost part
of the city opens up to Tharnadia's port beaches, where one can take a
casual stroll to take in the salty ocean air. Be careful there, though, the
beach can be dangerous to those caught unaware. On the beach itself lies
Bradistock Manor, famous for the haunting tales that keep many Tharnadian
children awake at night. The southern part of the city is renowned for its
seedy back-alleys, thugs and criminals. Far enough south, however, and the
beach can once again be found leading to the lighthouse and Tranquility
island. Leaving the Inn to the east going towards the gates of the city,
you can't help but notice the sites and smells of the local Baazar.
Travelers from all around stop to sample the wares sold here. North of the 
Baazar is a Bank and the magnificent Temple of the Paladins, where all are
welcome to stop and rest up awhile. Before leaving the city make sure to
stop and rent a mount for the journey for a trip across Goodie Continent
can be a tiring one!

Traveling out of the city on the Grand Tharnadia Way you will pass through
it's beautiful forest filled with a variety of animal life, ponds and
walking trails.
</content>
	<see-also file="hometowns"/>
</help-file>
