<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>THIEF</title>
	<category type="Specialization"/>
<content>
Thieves are masters of stealth, deceit, concealment, and they'll relieve
you of your valuables if you don't watch your purse. The main cause of
thieves is to take what is yours and to make it their own, preferably
without their victims knowing about it. But if backed into a corner,
thieves can be deadly enemies and are more than capable of fighting their
way out of tight spots. The dreaded thief is also renowned for its ability
to pick locks, alter their identity, to vanish into the shadows, not to
mention hunting their prey to the ends of the world to get what they want.

Thieves are held fully to the rules listed in Help Raid for equipment
guidelines, and while engaged in pstealing or pkilling they are considered
&quot;primary&quot; characters and as such must wear the best equipment available up
to and including removing equipment from their other characters to meet
these guidelines. This DOES include artifacts, uniques, and iouns, *unless*
they are not usable by a thief.  

ALL items stolen by a thief must be worn by the thief *unless* they cannot
use the object or are currently wearing better in that slot, in which case
it may be stored or given away.

ALL slots must be filled on a thief when at all possible, this includes
removing pieces of equipment from other characters that may not make much
sense on a thief.

For example, if you have the max_int ioun on another character, you MUST
remove it and put it on your thief when playing it. The only exception is
if the thief is currently wearing another ioun.

Thieves CANNOT be shared by multiple players at once. If any thief is found
being shared, they will be terminated whether or not the owner is online. 
Trying to get by these rules will be met with harsh consequences. If you
are unsure about what is legal or not, ask a god.

Skills
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
30th: Trip
30th: Dirttoss
30th: Listen
30th: Feign Death
36th: Enhanced Riposte
51st: Hamstring
56th: Evade
</content>
	<see-also file="rogue"/>
	<see-also file="skillrogue"/>
	<see-also file="classes"/>
	<see-also file="skills"/>
	<see-also file="assassin"/>
	<see-also file="bravo"/>
</help-file>
