<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<help-file>
	<title>THRI-KREEN</title>
	<category type="General Information"/>
<content>
Thri-Kreen are sometimes called &quot;Mantis Warriors&quot; they are an insect race
that looks very much like a giant praying mantis, only with 4 praying arms
and 2 legs for walking. The Thri-Kreen are about 7 feet tall and up to 11
feet long, however they do not weight much, and are there for considered
medium in size. 

Thri-Kreen are desert dwelling nomadic warriors that are neutral in most of
their dealings with other races. On Duris, this means that some of them will
be with the forces of good, some with evil.

Thri-Kreen having 4 arms 4 hands and thus, can wield up to 4 weapons at a
time including 2 2-handed weapons, or a bow and 2 weapons or any combo.
Thri-Kreen can also wear 4 sets of wrist-eq, 2 sets of hand wear, 2 sets of
sleeve eq. But they have no true fingers, and no ears. So they can not wear
any ear-rings or normal finger rings, and due to the odd nature of their
body and feet, they can not wear anything on their feet or body armor.

Thri-Kreen are a neutral born race, which means they can pick the path in
life in which they will walk, so, a Thri-Kreen must chose this path when he
is created.

Class list:       Warrior.
Statisticss:      Quite strong, tall and thin, very quick, also very high
                  in agility and very high dex. they are swift and fearsome
                  warriors.
Innate abilities: infravision, ultravision, leap, poison bite.

Thri-Kreen are extremely vulnerable to the cold and cold-based spells, the 
shock to their systems may in many cases even cause minor paralysis. Due to
their exoskeletal nature, thri-kreen are somewhat weaker than endoskeletal
races, and therefore will not receive certain stat bonus granted by various
spells and active skills.
</content>
	<see-also file="races"/>
	<see-also file="racewars"/>
	<see-also file="innate"/>
	<see-also file="infravision"/>
	<see-also file="ultravision"/>
</help-file>
